What is this?
这是啥
Nerve signals in the brain are always depicted like this.
大脑里的神经信号总是被描绘成这种样子
But, what is actually going on here?
但是，究竟发生了什么呢
Well, if you open a textbook, it's this complicated mechanism:
如果你翻开课本  会看到一堆复杂的机制
potentials, many different ions, chemical and electrical gradients...
动作电位、各种离子一大堆、化学成分和带电的成分……
It's a lot.
太多了
But, the basic principle of how nerve signals work is actually very straightforward.
不过  神经信号基本的工作原理  其实非常简单
细胞体
细胞过程（轴突）
So, I came up with a model that's using marbles that you can understand intuitively.
所以  我用弹珠搞了个模型  你就能直观地感受了
弹珠（离子）
通道
电梯（离子泵）
Okay, here goes.
走起
So, the cell puts out a few marbles
细胞先放进来一小批弹珠
and if there's enough of them, they can trigger a channel to open and
一旦弹珠数量足够  就能触发一个通道开启
more marbles pour in and are immediately pumped back out by the elevators.
让更多的弹珠进来  再通过电梯来泵回去
But a few reach the next section,
但还有少部分弹珠到了下一个通道处
where they trigger the next channel and more marbles pour in
他们会触发了下一个通道  又让更多弹珠进来
and they spread further, and so on.
这些弹珠会跑得更远 以此类推
So, this way, the signal travels on until it reaches the end.
信号通过这样一直传递下去  直至到达终点
This is the basic principle of nerve signals.
这就是神经信号的基本原理
And as long as you're alive, that is, as long as the elevators are working,
只要你还有一口气  或者说“电梯”还能工作
this can repeat over and over.
大脑里的信号就会不断在传递
So now, next time you see this, you know what's really going on.
下次你再见到这种动画时  你就知道是在干啥了